Guide to the Peter Štanský Papers SC0190
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-007
  - George Orwell subject files, 1953-2005
    Peter Štanský researched and presented papers on George Orwell (1903-1950) throughout his career as a professor and historian. This subject file includes Štanský’s manuscripts, correspondence, and research related to George Orwell.
    - Manuscripts (1 of 2), 1953-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts (2 of 2), 1953-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1982-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Research (1 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Research (2 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Research (3 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Forum: George Orwell, 2000 Nov 13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Today Show program on Orwell's 1984, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd)
  - Sassoon subject files, 1998-2009
    Two members of the prominent Sassoon family, Philip Sassoon (1888-1939) and his sister Sybil Sassoon (1894-1989) became the subject of one of his Peter Štanský’s many books. Sassoon: The Worlds of Philip and Sybil was published in 2003. This subject file contains book reviews of this publication, along with Štanský’s manuscripts, research, and correspondence related to the Sassoon family.
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Research (1 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Research (2 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Sassoon: The Worlds of Philip and Sybil book reviews, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    This subject file contains miscellaneous papers, most but not all of which were written by Peter Štanský.
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-167
  - Lyman Stanksy, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Birch Wathen High School - Archway Yearbook, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Birch Wathen High School - Archway Yearbook, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Birch Wathen High School - Archway Yearbook, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Re: Trip Across America, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Birch Wathen High School, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Last Words and Music, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale Memorial Programs, 1988-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History 80 Paper, 1952 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale 252nd Commencement Program, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Men, Art, and Politics" by Stanksy (Yale Thesis), 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yale - The Old Campus, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yale Class Book, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yale Class of 1953 Biographies (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yale Class of 1953 20th Reunion, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yale Class of 1953, 30th Reunion Yearbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 75: A Study of Generation in Transition, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photograph Allam, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Book Reviews and Manuscripts, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Peter Stanksy - Hair, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Incoming Letters, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Incoming Letters, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Incoming Letters, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Incoming Letters, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Incoming Letters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Incoming Letters, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Incoming Letters, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Incoming Letters, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Incoming Letters, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Incoming Letters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Incoming Letters, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Incoming Letters, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Incoming Letters, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Incoming Letters, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Incoming Letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Incoming Letters, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Incoming Letters, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Incoming Letters, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Incoming Letters, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Incoming Letters, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Incoming Letters, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Incoming Letters, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Incoming Letters, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Incoming Letters, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Incoming Letters, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Incoming Letters, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Incoming Letters, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Incoming Letters, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Incoming Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - News Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Morris and Asbhee - MSS Correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sposs/Stanksy Redesigning the World, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Outgoing Letters to Lyman Stanksy, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lecture Nutil, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lectures, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lectures, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lectures, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Personal, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Europe Summer MTI, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sophomore College, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Class Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lecture, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Personal Letters - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Varsey Family, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous - Personal, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 1952, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - The Expulsion of the Jews from France in 1306 and their Readmission in 1315, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Graded Class Papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lord Lyttelton and Edward Thring, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Looking for a Lameale, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Personal Letters and Postcards, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Publications (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and materials from Yale, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Golden Years album (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Sposs Stansky, Redesigning the World (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - London Burning, colored by Brigette Carnochan (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Flag Day, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Event posters (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photograph (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prints: New Yorker, George Orwell (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - William Miller Abrahams ephemera (Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Marina Vaizey clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Marina Vaizey clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Marina Vaizey clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Trip - American youth hostels, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Peter Grimes by George Crabbe, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Susan, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Peter/Bill, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letters to/from Bill, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lyman Slansky, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - miscellaneous clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - letters from family, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Pacific coast conference of British studies, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letters from Billy, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Genealogical, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "The Duke of Newcastle, Cambridge, and the Church" Bowdoin, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - History 242 paper by Štanský, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Summer correspondence, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Summer correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with Billy, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Štanský reprints, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - American Academy of Arts + Sciences, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Harvard/Kirkland house, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - William Morris, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Stanford Humanities Center, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Honors and Awards, undated (Box 7, Folder 0)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-060
  - Research files for Štanský's book "Edward Upward: Art and Life", 1930s-2015 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1)